pharmacychecker.com 2019-07-30

# Privacy Policy | PharmacyChecker.com

PharmacyChecker.com respects your privacy.

This policy pertains to use of our website, [www.pharmacychecker.com](https://www.pharmacychecker.com/) (the “Site”), by the public at large.

We are based in the United States, but the Site’s visitors come from just about every country. We have created our privacy policy to comply with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation, which is the world’s strictest regulation protecting privacy at this time. We are proud to be following best practices in this area.

First thing's first:  **We do  not sell, rent, or trade, any information that you provide to us, and PharmacyChecker.com collects little to no personal information about you.**

Like most websites, we use what are called “cookies” to track your session and improve your online experience. We do not use that information to personally identify you. See the below section,  _What Cookies Collect_ , for details.

You have the option to sign up for our free services, but you are not required to do so. If you do use our services, the personal information that you provide is very limited. This information is detailed below in the section, Services.

## Services

Site Services (“Services”) are those that you can sign up for by creating a user name and password. They are free, and you will not need to provide any financial information. The Services offered include:

Price Alerts: Price Alerts allow you to sign up to receive email notifications (every month or every three months) alerting you of the latest prices posted on the Site for a drug or drugs you have selected.

The information we collect if you sign up for Price Alerts:

  * Email address
  * Password
  * Drug Name (i.e. Advair Diskus, Januvia, Lipitor, Nexium, or Viagra)
  * Drug Strength (i.e. 20 mg, 100 mg, etc.)
  * Frequency of Alert (i.e. 30 days, 90 days)

Newsletter: The Site’s free newsletter alerts you of important news regarding online pharmacies, drug prices, and personal drug importation.

The information we collect if you sign up for the Newsletter:

  * Email address

Consumer Ratings and Comments: Using Consumer Ratings and Comments, you can rate and comment on your experience with a PharmacyChecker-verified online pharmacy.

The information we collect if you choose to rate and comment on a PharmacyChecker-verified online pharmacy:

  * Feedback Username
  * Email Address
  * Comments

Ask PharmacyChecker: Ask PharmacyChecker gives patients the opportunity to ask our panel of experts a question about online pharmacies, prescription savings, drug importation, and related issues.

The information we collect if you sign up for Ask PharmacyChecker:

  * First name
  * Last name
  * Email address
  * Question (the question that you ask)
  * Comments (if any)

My PharmacyChecker: Using My PharmacyChecker, you can create an identity with PharmacyChecker to use all the services mentioned above.

The information we collect if you sign up for My PharmacyChecker:

  * First name
  * Last name
  * Email address
  * Password

## What Cookies Collect

Generally, from your visit to the Site, we may record your IP address, web browser, what products you searched for to compare prices, and links that you clicked on to go to other sites. During that process, we use a cookie, but the cookie expires at the end of your session on the Site.

During the Site’s Services registration process and use, including when you change your registration information, your computer must accept a cookie. If your browser is set to notify you when you receive a cookie, you'll be prompted to accept the cookie (Yes/No). To use the Services, you must select “Yes” if you would like to avoid having to enter your username and password on every screen while using our Services. If you accept, the cookie will be saved to your device and will not be used for any purpose other than automatic login.

**You can remove cookies at any time by clearing your cache.**

PharmacyChecker.com may conduct surveys to better understand our users. All survey information is voluntarily disclosed and will not be associated with the individual users. Cookies are used to track what surveys already have been presented, to avoid users from being presented with or submitting duplicate surveys.

We use Google Analytics to evaluate Site usage by analyzing user information in the aggregate, but we do not use that information to identify any individual user. In our use of Google Analytics and including Google Analytics Interests and Demographics, we measure visits to the Site, such as number of visits, pages visited, location of visitors (i.e. New York State, Mexico, Europe), entrance and exit pages. Google places a cookie on your device that expires 24 months after your last visit to PharmacyChecker.com, which is used to collect anonymous browsing data, including demographics data. This is used to develop content for our users. You can opt out of this through your browser settings or by visiting this webpage: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

## Information that you share with us other than through the Site

We sometimes assist people who use the Site by answering their questions and helping resolve possible customer disputes with pharmacies. You may voluntarily choose to email or communicate by phone information that is personal. We cannot control what you send to us. Unless you give us express permission to do so, we will never share that information with third parties, unless compelled to do so through government request.

## Marketing Partners

We work with marketing partners who feed local U.S. pharmacy drug prices to us. This information is only relevant to people living in the U.S. If you choose to enter your ZIP Code on the Site to compare local pharmacy prices, print out a discount card/coupon, and use it to fill a prescription, then the relevant marketing partner will be able to track the purchase associated with that ZIP Code and card, but will not be able to associate that information to your name.

## Links to other websites

We link to other websites. This includes online pharmacies, government websites, and other online information sources. We have no control over those websites and their privacy policies, except those owned and operated by PharmacyChecker (PharmacyCheckerBlog.com and MedicareDrugPlans.com).

## Sharing information with service providers

In signing up for our Services, we work with an email and newsletter distribution company to help us effectively provide the service. That service provider is located in the United States and only has access to your name and email address, which are only used for our Services.

## How to remove your information

You can get PharmacyChecker.com to remove your personal and any other information about you from our databases by contacting us at privacy@pharmacychecker.com . We will remove such information within one month of your request. That information will be limited to your name, username, password, and email address.

## How to request your personal information

You can request your personal information from PharmacyChecker.com by emailing us at [privacy@pharmacychecker.com](mailto:privacy@pharmacychecker.com); including in the Subject line “My personal information request” and including in the body of the email the username associated with your account.

We will then provide you with the personal data that is stored in the PharmacyChecker.com database in a comma-separated values (CSV) text file that can be imported into commonly used spreadsheet programs. That information will include name, username, and email address. We will not send a password, however, to prevent misuse and identify theft, but we will delete your password from our system within 30 days of your request to do so.

## How PharmacyChecker.com stores personal information data

### Security of your information:

PharmacyChecker.com uses encryption, security protocols, and other industry-standard information technology best practices to maintain the security of company computer systems, databases and user data. For example, we employ secure socket layer (SSL) encryption on all pages to protect all visitors to the Site from unauthorized and unwanted intrusions and unlawful efforts by third parties to view your personal information or any information about you at all.

When you look at the Site, you can tell that all pages have a “secure connection” by looking for the following indicators on your browser:

  * A security alert window tells you that you are about to use a secure connection. Some browsers let you choose whether to display this window.
  * An SSL icon shows when you're using a secure connection: 
    * A symbol of an open padlock changes to a closed padlock when you're in a secure connection.
    * A symbol of a “broken key” icon is replaced by an unbroken key.
    * A blue line runs across the top of the content window.
  * The Site's address changes to one that begins with “https”; (check for the “s”).

The encrypted data is directed to a secure site, where your information is stored on a private computer that is not directly accessible via the Internet.

If you have questions about this policy, please email us at [privacy@pharmacychecker.com](mailto:privacy@pharmacychecker.com). Thank you for using PharmacyChecker.com!

Updated October 4, 2018
